Evangelos Constantinou

214 David Kinley Hall 1407 W. Gregory Drive Urbana, IL 61801, USA Phone: +1 (217) 721-5834 Email: ecnstnt2@illinois.edu

Website: evangelosconstantinou.com

Citizen: Cyprus, U.S. Legal Permanent Resident

SUMMARY

Economics PhD candidate specializing in Industrial Organization, Applied Econometrics, and Political Economy with extensive experience working with Big Data, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, and Cloud Services. Familiar with different programming and scripting languages. Proficient at economic modeling, empirical industrial organization, structural and reduced-form econometric techniques.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign IL

PhD Economics 2022 (expected)

University of Oxford, Oxford, United Kingdom

MPhil Economics 2012

University of Warwick, United Kingdom

BSc Economics 2010

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Industrial Organization, Applied Econometrics, Structural Microeconometrics, Political Economy

SKILLS

Statistical: R, Stata, Mathematica, Matlab

Programming/Scripting: Python, Shell, JavaScript (basic)

Markup: Latex, Markdown, Org, HTML, CSS

Languages: English (fluent), Greek (mother tongue), Italian (very poor).

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign IL

Research Assistant to Prof. George Deltas

Aug 2015 - May 2022

- Design empirical and theoretical models to address questions gas prices, switching costs and voting order.
- Execute reduced-form and structural econometric models.
- Author articles summarizing and providing intuition of results for effective communication with other team members.

University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus

Research Assistant to Prof. Sofronis Clerides

June 2011 - Aug 2011, May 2013 - Aug 2014

- Compose and clean novel databases to answer questions related to consumer inattention.
- Author technical reports in an accessible manner for effective communication with lead investigator and general audience.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign IL

Head Teaching Assistant, Microeconomic Principles

2016 - 2019

- Lead and coordinate a team of teaching assistants.
- Responsible for communicating the lecturer's directions to teaching assistants and students.
- Conflict resolution between teaching assistants, and teaching assistants and students.
- Accessible and effective communication of complex ideas to new students of the subject.

University of Cyprus, Nicosia, Cyprus

Special Teaching Staff

2012 - 2014

- Independently devised teaching material for multitude of classes.
- Responsible for evaluating the progress of students.

RESEARCH

Publications

- 1. "The price-matching dilemma", with Dan Bernhardt. *International Journal of Industrial Organization*, Vol. 59, 2018, pp. 97–113.
- 2. "When do co-located firms selling identical products thrive?", with Dan Bernhardt and Mehdi Shadmehr. Forthcoming at *Journal of Industrial Economics*.

Working Papers and Work in progress

- 1. "Messaging the Bases: Tailoring Political Ads to Audiences" (Job Market Paper)
- 2. "Candidate Advertising Free Riding and Party Solutions".
- 3. "Endogenous Order with Sequential Elections", with George Deltas.
- 4. "Name-Change Fees, Scalpers, and Secondary Markets".
- 5. "Airline Entry and Switching Costs", with George Deltas.

Other

"Has Foreign Direct Investment exhibited sensitiveness to crime across countries in the period 1999-2004? And if so, is this effect non-linear?", *Undergraduate Economic Review*: Vol. 7: Iss. 1, Article 15.

AWARDS & HONORS

Dissertation Completion Fellowship, Graduate College, University of Illinois	2021-2022
Summer Research Fellowship, University of Illinois	2016, 2017
Cleo Fitzsimmons Award (awarded to best student in PhD cohort), University of Illinois	2016
List of Excellent Teachers, University of Illinois	2015, 2017
Member of Phi Kappa Phi	2016
Graduate Fellowship, University of Illinois	2014
Excellence Cyprus State Scholarship for Graduate Studies	2011

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Referee: Social Choice and Welfare; Journal of Environmental and Resource Economics; Journal of Industry, Competition and Trade.

Seminars and Presentations

2018: UIUC, International Industrial Organization Conference (IIOC) **2019** and **2020**: Seminars at UIUC **2021** (Virtual): PhD EVS, UIUC, Southern Economic Association (SEA) (upcoming)

REFERENCES

Prof. Dan Bernhardt	Prof. George Deltas	Prof. Stefan Krasa
Department of Economics	Department of Economics	Department of Economics
UIUC	UIUC	UIUC
⊠ danber@illinois.edu	⊠ deltas@illinois.edu	⋈ skrasa@illinois.edu

Last updated: November 30, 2021